{"data":[{"question":"Jim had just turned out the lights when the doorbell ________.","a":"rings","b":"rang","c":"has rung","d":"had rung","answer":"2","explain":"\n- Simple past tense\/past perfect tense + while\/when + simple past tense.\u00a0","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"18","subcategorylv2":"18","type":"1"},{"question":"I work so hard that I ________ tired.","a":"am","b":"was","c":"be","d":"has been","answer":"1","explain":"\n- I work so hard: simple present tense- result (tired) must be in simple present tense.\u00a0","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"18","subcategorylv2":"18","type":"1"},{"question":"I'll return the books to the library if I ________ time.","a":"have","b":"had","c":"will have","d":"would have","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Condition type I: If + simple present, simple future tense\/simple present tense.","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"18","subcategorylv2":"18","type":"1"},{"question":"Richard left dirty footmarks wherever he ________.","a":"go","b":"goes","c":"went","d":"had gone","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Richard left dirty footmarks: is simple past tense- wherever he __________ must be simple past tense.\u00a0","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"18","subcategorylv2":"18","type":"1"},{"question":"I worked so hard that I ________ tired.","a":"am","b":"was","c":"be","d":"has been","answer":"2","explain":"\n- I worked so hard : is simple past tense- I __________ tired: must be simple past tense.","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"18","subcategorylv2":"18","type":"1"},{"question":"Don't handle those cups and saucers as if they ________ made of iron.","a":"are","b":"were","c":"has been","d":"had been","answer":"2","explain":"\n- Clauses that start with as if\/as though express unreality, improbability or doubt if they are followed by an unreal tense.\u00a0\n- The simple past tense is used if we talk about an unreal situation in the present.\u00a0","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"18","subcategorylv2":"18","type":"1"},{"question":"I am standing where I ________ the game.","a":"can see","b":"could see","c":"can't see","d":"couldn't see","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Where I __________ the game: Is the purpose of action \"I am standing\"= Where I __________ the game: must be in present tense.\u00a0\n- This sentence imply that the speaker wants to see the game (positive).\u00a0","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"18","subcategorylv2":"18","type":"1"},{"question":"Use the paint-brush as I ________ you yesterday.","a":"show","b":"showed","c":"had showed","d":"has showed","answer":"2","explain":"\n- Simple past tense: Use the Simple Past to express the idea that an action started and finished at a specific time in the past (yesterday).\u00a0","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"18","subcategorylv2":"18","type":"1"},{"question":"Everywhere I ________ there were dirty footmarks.","a":"look","b":"looked","c":"has looked","d":"will look","answer":"2","explain":"\n- There were dirty footmarks: simple present tense- Everywhere I ________ must be in simple present tense.","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"18","subcategorylv2":"18","type":"1"},{"question":"We couldn't play the match because the frog ________ too thick.","a":"is","b":"be","c":"was","d":"will be","answer":"3","explain":"\n- The frog ________ too thick: Is the cause of action \"We couldn't play the match \" (simple past)= the frog ________ too thick:must be in simple past tense. ","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"18","subcategorylv2":"18","type":"1"}]}